
This file contains description of the MATLAB files used in the "The Value Premium"
published in the JOurnal of Finance, 60 (1) 67-103.

© Lu Zhang, Simon School, University of Rochester and NBER


. CalibCC.m --- Calibrates all the parameter values in the model
      
      This file calls rouwTrans.m that discretize the continuous AR(1)
      productivity process into a discrete state space. I use the Rouwenhorst (1995, in
      Frontiers of business cycle research) method because the persistence level 
      is close to one. When the persistence level is so high, the usual Tauchen and 
      Hussey method does not work well

      This file also calls two subroutines to construct the Sharpe ratio and 
      real interest rate on the grid

. mainCC.m --- Solves the value function iteration and the industry equilibrium
      using the approximate aggregation method of Krusell and Smith (1998, JPE)

      This file calls vfi3fcnIEcc.dll and simIEfcn3.dll that are MATLAB MEX files 
      written in Fortran 90. vfi3fcnIEcc.dll solves for the value function using the 
      value function iteration algorithm. And simIEfcn3.dll simulates artificial data on
      output price, aggregate capital, and average firm-specific productivity in the 
      time series

. ssIE.m --- Simulate the cross-section of firms until stationary distribution

. panIE.m --- Simulate repeately panel data from the cross-sectional distribution of 
      firms and perform various empirical analysis to generate model moments to be 
      compared with data moments